자막제작 - 코리아닷컴 프렌즈 동호회 (http://club.korea.com/friends)
Hi guys,
안녕,얘들아!
Hi~
응,왔어?
-Hey -Hey
We need to talk to you about something
니들한테 할말이 있어
Yeah. We don't feel like we can host thanksgiving this year.
이번 추수 감사절은 우리 집에서 안 할거야
-What? Why? -What? Are you kidding?
뭐?
농담이겠지?
Well, just with the work and stress of adoption, we just don't feel like we have the energy.
회사다 입양이다 치어 살아서 그럴 여유가 없을것 같아
Plus we don't think it's fair that every year the burden falls on us.
게다가 매년 우리만 일하는 것도 불공평하잖아
That doen't sound like you.
네 말투가 아닌데?
That's monica talking!
모니카 말투잖아!
no, no
아냐, 우리둘이 같이 결정 한거야
We made this decision together.
She's putting words in your mouth!
모니카가 시킨 말이잖아!
그런 말 하게 만들지 말고 칠면조나 만들어 줘!
Don't you put words in people's mouths. You put turkey in people's mouths.
어떻게 에마의 첫 번째 추수 감사절에 이럴 수가 있어?
I can't believe this. This is Emma's first thanksgiving.
No, it's not.
첫 번째는 아니야
It's not?
아니라고?
When was she born?
에마의 생일이 언제더라?
Well, personally, I think it's great you're giving yourself a break.
내 생각엔 올 해는 너도 쉬는게 좋을 것 같아
Thank you, pheebs.
고마워,피비
Sure.
그럼
It's just as well, I mean, last year wasn't very good. I think she's losing her touch.
어차피 작년에도 별로 였잖아 이제 감각이 떨어졌나 봐
뭐?말도 안돼!
what?! You are way off, lady!
Am I? Really? Am I?
진짜?정말? 과연 그럴까?
Well, why don't you cook thanksgiving dinner and prove me wrong?
그럼 이번에 요리를 해서 내가 틀렸다고 증명해 보시지?
Well, think about it. think about it.
생각을 해봐, 작년보다 더 잘하면 되잖아
You'd be trying to top what you did last year. You'd be in a competition with yourself.
자기 자신과 싸움이라고
내가 제일 좋아하는거야 그래,하겠어!
That's my favorite kind.
Okay, we are doing this!
Don't let yourself get manipulated this way.
이런 식으로 이용당하지 마
Stay out of this, chandler!
자긴 여기서 빠져 이건 나와 나 자신과의 싸움이라고!
This is between me and me!
항상 상의 해서 행동하기로 했잖아
We are supposed to make these decisions together.
내가 녹화해 준 부부상담프로 안 본거야?
Did you not watch the dr. Phil I taped for you?
FㆍRㆍIㆍEㆍNㆍDㆍS
10x08 The One With The Late Thanksgiving
한글번역 오종현(hiro97@hanmir.com)
코리아닷컴 프렌즈동호회
테스트 단형철(divine0422@freechal.com)
대본 - 문정원(chris718)
싱크 변정주(jungjoo@kaist.ac.kr)
수정 - 강효진(riverkei) 싱크 - 변정주(mechanic)
추수 감사절 잘 보내!
-Hey. -Hi. Happy thanksgiving!
Oh, yeah, happy needless turkey murder day.
그래, 너도 쓸데 없는 칠면조 살인의 날 잘보내!
Hehey, guys, I ordered some chocolate pies from that bakery on bleeker.
내가 블러커가에 있는 제과점에 초코렛 파이를 주문했거든?
Could you pick them up for me?
그것 좀 가져다 줄래?
You're not making the pies yourself?
파이는 니가 안 만들어?
난 초코렛 파이는 안 만들어 어릴 때 파이먹기 대회에 나갔었는데
No, I don't make chocolate pies.
When I was younger, I entered this pie eating contest and I ate so many that just the ouought of them makes me sick.
그 때 너무 많이 먹어서 이제는 생각만 해도 토할 것 같거든
Did you at least win the contest?
대회에서 이기긴 했어?
Two minutes, 12 pies, and a part of one tin.
2분 만에 12조각을 먹고 접시도 좀 드셨지
Okay, I'll see you guys at 4:00.
그럼, 4시에 보자
기대되네
Can't wait.
This dinner is going to be so great.
오늘 저녁은 대단할거야 작년의 모니카! 각오하라고!
In your face, last year me!
Hey, rach, what's Emma today?
레이첼,에마는 오늘 뭐해?
어디 보자..
Well, let's see uh, I know that she has a meeting with her lawyer,
일단 변호사랑 상담을 하고 그 다음엔 크게 한번 응가도 해야지
and then she has to make a very big poop.
Why?
근데 왜?
Well, I want to enter her in a baby beauty pageant.
아기 미인 대회에 내보내려고
Oh, my god.
어머나! 그렇게 괴상한건 처음 들어보네!
That's the creepiest thing I've ever heard.
거절하기 전에 먼저 들어봐
Okay, but before you say no, my friend Suzanne is entering her kid and compared to Emma,
내 친구 수잔도 걔 애를 내보내는데 에마랑 비교하면 쨉도 안돼
she's a real dog.
Oh! Phoebe, all babies are beautiful.
피비, 아이들은 다 예쁜거야
Uh, okay.
그러시겠지
애들끼리만 모아놓고 누가 더 예쁜지나 보고 겨우 트로피 하나에 그러는 건..
Just the idea of pitting one baby against another,
I mean, you know, judging who's cuter just for a trophy...
and $1,000.
게다가 천 달러까지
...Is something I'm very interested in.
정말 구미가 땡기는 일이지!
절대 로스에게는 얘기하지 마
Oh, please, do not tell ross.
로스는 내면의 미가 더 중요하다느니 그런 걸 믿잖아
He still believes that what's on the inside is important.
아, 그리고 대회에는 에마를 여자 카우보이처럼 입혀서 보내야 돼
Okay. Ooh, Emma needs a cowgirl outfit for the competition.
Where am I going to get a cowgirl outfit on thanksgiving?
추수 감사절에 그런걸 어서 구해?
Well, I was thinking...
내 생각엔..
Take the clothes off joey's cabbage patch kid!
조이 인형 옷을 쓰면 되겠다! /그렇지
Yeah!
Did someone drop the baton again?
또 누가 지휘봉을 떨어 뜨렸어?
Why come all the way from kansas to do that?
저러려면 왜 켄자스에서 여기까지 온 거야?
나이가 드는게 아니라 실력만 느는구만
I don't get older, I just get better.
You know what just occurred to me?
자기 그거 알아? 이번이 우리 둘이 하는 마지막 추수 감사절일거야
This could be our last thanksgiving just the two of us.
I mean, we could be getting a baby soon.
곧 입양할 지도 모르잖아
You don't know that.
그걸 어떻게 알아
Somebody's going to pick us.
누군가 걸리겠지
Yeah, but we haven't heard a thing from the adoption agency, and it's been weeks.
입양 복지 사무소에서도 몇 주 동안 연락이 없잖아
나만 믿어 꼭 연락이 올거야
I'm telling you, it's going to happen.
내년엔 자기랑 나랑 우리 헤밍웨이 빙이 같이 살거야
Next year, it's going to be you, me and little hemingway bing.
What? He's my favorite author.
왜? 내가 제일 좋아하는 작가라고
책 이름 하나만 대봐
Name one of his books.
The firm?
'야망의 함정?'
자, 칠면조는 오븐에 넣고 소고기 속도 했고
Okay, let's see.
Okay, the turkey's in the oven, the stuffing is ready...
You know, you always cook this meal all by yourself.
있지,음식은 매번 자기만 하잖아 이번엔 나도 도울께
Let me help this year.
Come on, chandler, That's sweet.
마음은 고마워, 자기야
But you don't have to do everything dr. Phil tells you to do.
그치만 그 부부 상담프로에 나온 대로 다 할 필요는 없잖아
I'm serious. Let me do something.
진짜야,뭔가 맡겨보라고 칠면조나 소고기 같은 거 말고 안 중요한 걸로 말야
Just not the turkey or the stuffing.
Nothing high-profile.
Okay, let's see.
그러지 뭐 아! 크렌베리 소스!
Oh, the cranberry sauce.
It's easy to make, and no one really cares about it.
만들기도 쉽고 사람들이 별로 신경도 안 써
Tell me more.
맘에 드는데
Okay, I'm going to go check on something across the hall.
조이집에 가서 뭣 좀 확인 할테니 자긴 이것부터 씻어
You start by washing these.
Not with soap!
세제는 쓰지 마!
You obviously haven't tasted my palmolive potatoes.
내 세제 감자요리는 못 먹어 봤나보지?
Hey, hey, guess what joey has?
조이가 뭘 가져왔는지 알아?
Three tickets to today's rangers game!
오늘 하키게임 표 세장!
Dude, I wanted him to guess.
챈들러보고 맞춰보라고 한거야
Oh.
Oh, my god!
이야!
Yeah, they're great seats, too.
자리도 끝내줘
Guess where they are.
어디 자린지 알아?
경기장 한 가운데지
Center ice.
Did I do something to you?
왜 자꾸 그래?
이거 1시 게임이잖아
Mmm, the game's at 1:00.
So?
그래서?
Dinner's at 4:00. We'll never make it back
저년 약속 4시니까 그때까진 못 돌아오잖아
게임 끝나기 전에 오면 제 시간에 올 꺼야
We'll leave before it's over. We'll be back in time.
You say that now, but it could take us a long time to get back home.
말은 그렇게 해도 오는데 시간이 오래 걸릴 수도 있잖아
Plus, Joey could get lost and they could have to page us to go pick him up.
또 조이가 길을 잃으면 삐삐 오길 기다렸다가 찾으러 가야 되잖아
Dude, two times that happened!
겨우 두 번 그랬잖아!
Look, monica's been working hard all day.
모니카가 하루 종일 일했다고 원랜 하기 싫다고 했었잖아 가면 안 된다니까
She didn't want to host this thing in the first place. We shouldn't go.
He's right, man
챈들러 말이 맞아
Yeah, I guess.
알았어,그럼 4시에 보자
All right, So we'll see you at 4:00.
Okay.
그래 내가 만든 크렌베리를 기대하라고
And get ready to taste my very special cranberries.
Or should I say... chanberries.
챈베리라고 부를까?
That's some gentle comedy, dude.
퍽 이나 재밌다, 임마
We're still going to the game, right?
그래도 우린 가는 거지?
그럼
-Yeah. -Yeah.
Our next contestant is number 16.
다음 참가자는 16번 입니다
Hey
피비,우리 가는 게 좋겠다 여긴 너무 이상해, 저기 있는 남자는 애도 없는데 왔다고
Oh, phoebe, listen, I think we got to go. This place is really freaking me out.
I've been watching this guy over there.
I don't think he came with a kid.
But we can't leave now.
이제 와서 그냥 갈 순 없어
There was this one baby, Hayley, who was favored to win, and she got croup, so she had to stay home.
유력한 우승자였던 헤일리가 후두염 때문에 못 왔단 말야
This competition just blew wide open, folks.
이길 가능성이 높아졌다고
그래도 싫어 방금 한살짜리가 팬티스타킹 신고 있는 것도 봤다고
Phoebe, it's just too weird.
I just saw a one-year-old running around with pantyhose on.
I know. We should have been more prepared.
그러게, 우리도 좀 더 준비했어야 하는 건데
It's okay.
그래도 괜찮아 내가 보기에 우리 라이벌은 카메론이야
Now, the way I see it, our real competition now is Cameron.
Oh, my god. They just took her sweater off.
어머, 방금 카메론의 스웨터를 벗겼어
Look at those arms. Hello, michelin man.
저 팔 좀 봐! 어이, 미셰린 타이어씨!
Oh, phoebe! Come on!
피비, 그만 좀 해!
You know, it's already 3:00.
벌써 3신데 우리 차례도 안 됐잖아 지금 안 가면 식사에 늦는다고
They haven't even gotten to Emma's group. We got to go. We got dinner.
But emma's got what it takes! She could go all the way!
에마는 할 수 있어! 이길 수 있다고!
Ok, Phoebe.
Phoebe, you have to calm down.
피비,진정해
Okay, rachel~
The hottest babies in the tri-state area are in this room right now.
시상대에 오를만한 애들은 지금 이 방에 있다고
I overheard one of the judges say that not one of them holds a candle to Emma.
에마만한 애가 없다고 심사위원들이 말하는 것도 들었어
-Really? -Yeah.
정말?
그래
You heard him say that?
정말 그랬어?
그렇다니까
Yeah.
All right. Okay.
좋아, 알았어
이 애들 좀 울려 보자고
All right, let's give these babies something to cry about.
그렇지!
Good! Okay!
그럼 시작해 볼까? 에마한테 화장 좀 시켜야겠다
Let's get down to business. Emma needs some makeup.
뭐라고?
What?!
다른 애들이랑 같이 서 있으면 너무 핏기 없어 보일거야
She's going to look all washed out next to the other contestants.
Phoebe, I am not letting you put makeup on my baby.
얘 한테 화장을 시킬 순 없어
Why not?
또 왜?
Because I already did!
내가 이미 했으니까!
-Oh! You bum! -Oh, you suck!
-그게 뭐야! -잘 좀 해보시지!
-Get off the ice! -You idiot!
-What a game! -I know!
정말 죽인다
그러게
I can't believe Chandler is missing this.
이걸 못 보다니 챈들러가 불쌍한걸?
Yeah, I'm sorry he's not here too, but I got to say, I am really enjoying nacho chair.
나도 불쌍하긴 하지만 이 나초 의자도 맘에 드는데
Yeah, I'd probably enjoy it more if you didn't keep batting my hand away.
니가 내 손만 안쳐내면 나도 맘에 들 텐데 말이지
Oh, yeah!
-These seats are great! -I know, I know.
여기 자리 끝내준다!
그러게 말야
When I was here for holidays on ice...
내가 여기 아이스 쇼 보러 왔을 때 말야
I was sitting so far away, Michelle Kwan couldn't read my banner.
너무 멀리 앉아서 미셸 콴이 내가 쓴 응원피켓도 못 봤다니까
Whoa, hey, we better get going.
이제 가야겠다 지금 안가면 저녁약속에 늦을거야
If we don't leave right now, we're going to be late for dinner.
아직 비기고 있잖아 여자 애들도 있는데 좀 늦으면 어때?
Oh, but it's a tie game.
So, we're a little late, you know?
The girls will be there. Let's just stay for one more goal.
한 골 만 더 나면 가자
I don't know.
글쎄..
-One more fight. -Okay -Okay
한 번 더 싸울 때 까지
그래
다들 어디간거야? 45분이나 늦었잖아
Where is everybody? They're 45 minutes late
I can't believe they're not here.
어떻게 애들이 이럴 수가 있지?
그렇게 애써서 일해 놨더니 말야
I slaved and I slaved for what?
내 크렌베리의 날을 망쳤잖아
They've ruined cranberry day!
얼마나 늦었지?
-How late are we? -45 minutes.
45분
-Wow. -Here.
레이첼이랑 피비가 있으니 우릴 빼고 시작했을지도 몰라
Rachel and phoebe are already there, okay?
So, they probably started without us. We can just slip in, and no one needs to know where we were.
그냥 살짝 들어가면 돼 어디 갔었는 지는 말하지 말고
You may want to lose the foam finger.
그 손가락 치우는 게 어때?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
그렇게 안되지? 니 손에 끼울려고 그러지?
You just want to put it on your hand.
-Hey. -Uhh
Oh!
안에 있던 거 아니었어?
You're not at thanksgiving?
-No! -No, we're late!
아니, 좀 늦었어
What are you doing here?!
너넨 여기서 뭐하는 거야?
We're late, too!
우리도 늦었지!
We figured we could be late because you guys would be on time.
너네가 같이 있을 줄 알고 늦은 거란 말이야!
Don't point that thing at me, tribbiani.
그 손가락 치우는게 좋을 걸!
So, nobody's here?! Monica's going to kill us.
그럼 아무도 안 온거야? 모니카가 죽이려고 들 거야!
Yeah, where were you?
어디 갔었어?
Yeah, what's with the trophy?
그래, 그 트로피는 뭐야?
Um, well, uh...
We were at a spelling bee.
철자 맟추기 게임하는 데 갔었어
And I won!
그리고 내가 이겼지!
You won an adult thanksgiving day spelling bee?
추수 감사절에 다 큰 여자들이 그런 게임 한다고?
그럼 ㄱ,ㅡ,ㄹ,ㅓ,ㅁ, 그럼!
Yes. Y-e-s-- yes.
Let me see this.
좀 보자
"Grand supreme little darling, New York division"?
이쁜 아기 미인대회 뉴욕지부
내가 나가서 이겼어!
That's me.
에마를 미인대회에 내보냈어?
You entered Emma in a beauty pageant?!
And it looks like she put makeup on her.
에마 화장까지 시킨 거 같은데?
잠깐 기다려 봐, 저 여자 카우보이 옷을 어디서 봤더라?
Wait a second, wait a second.
Where have I seen that cowgirl outfit before?
I can't believe this. She's our daughter.
우리 딸을 애견대회 같은데 보내는 건 용서할 수 없어!
That you would treat her like some kind of show dog is inexcusable!
She won $1,000!
천 달러를 땄다고!
So, this is an annual thing?
이거 매년 하는 거야?
That's Alicia May Emory's outfit!
이거 내 인형 옷이잖아!
우리가 이런다고 안에 있는 애들이 좋아하겠어?
You guys, there are people in there who are not getting any happier.
Yeah, what are we going to do?
이제 어떡하지?
I don't know. You guys figure it out.
글쎄, 생각 좀 해봐 난 에마를 재우고 올께
I got to put Emma down for her nap.
레이첼, 들어간 김에 인형한테 옷 좀 입혀!
And Rach, while you're in there, throw something on Alicia May!
쟤들한테 뭐라고 하지?
What are we going to say?
Ooh! We'll say that we were mugged.
강도를 만났다고 하면 되겠다!
You can't get mad at someone who's been mugged.
강도를 만났다는데 화를 내진 않겠지
Good, that's good.
그거 좋겠다
But you don't look like you were mugged.
근데 강도한테 당한 것 처럼 보이질 안잖아
No. Here.
자
Hey!
야!
Do you hear something?
무슨 소리 안 들려?
저 밖에 다 있어!
They're out there!
나도 좀 봐!
Let me see!
Oh, my god, I can't believe this.
어떻게 늦은 주제에 밖에서 수다나 떨 수가 있지?
They're an hour late, and they're just standing out there talking!
애들이 울그러져서 보여
Everything is so distorted.
조이 손가락이 커진 것 같은데
It looks like joey has a giant hand.
That says Rangers on it.
레인저스라고 써 있다 하키보러 간 거야!
They went to the game!
Oh, they are in for a world of pain.
단단히 각오들은 했겠지?
로스의 셔츠가 찢어졌는데?
Ross' shirt is torn
They're late, and they're sloppy!
늦은 주제에 옷도 그 따위라고?
All right, Emma's napping.
에마는 재웠어 셔츠가 왜 그래?
What happened to your shirt?
I got mugged, and they stole my pocket.
강도가 내 윗주머니를 털었어
변명을 만드는 중이야
We're trying to figure out an excuse.
그럼 이건 어때?
Hey, oh, how about this?
모니카가 4시가 아니라 5시라고 했다고 우기면 늦은 게 아니잖아
We could say that monica told us 5:00, not 4:00.
That way, we're right on time.
아니면!
Or...
Or we could plant pcp in the apartment and call the cops on her.
얘네 아파트에 대마초를 심고 경찰에 신고해 버리는 거야
그럼 이제 남은 대마초는 잘도 처리할 수 있겠구나!
That would be a good way to get rid of all the pcp we have lying around.
You know what, We'll just say that she said it was 5:00.
그냥 5시라고 했다고 우기자고
We'll just act casual. We're not late. We're right on time.
시침 뚝 떼고 안 늦은 척 하는거야
'나는 너희가 거기 있는걸 알고 있다'
"We know you're out there."
이게 누구한테 온 걸까?
Who do you think it's from?
Oh, god, this is bad. This is so bad.
우린 이제 큰일났다 정말 큰일 났어!
Well, let's just go in there and face them.
그냥 들어가서 부딪혀 보자
난 먼저 안 들어갈래
Well, I'm not going in first. I bet that vein on monica's forehead is popping like crazy.
분명 모니카 이마에 핏줄이 불끈 섰을거야
나 그거 정말 싫어 꼭 번개치는 모양이라고
Yeah, I hate that thing. It's like a bolt of lightning.
이건 어때? 가위. 바위.보를 해서 진 사람이 먼저 들어가자
Oh, hey, I have an idea.
Why don't we play rock, paper, scissors, and whoever loses goes in first.
-좋아 -그게 좋겠어
-Okay. -All right, I'm in.
준비
Ready?
하하! 내가 이겼다!
Ha, ha! I win!
그게 뭐야?
What is that?
불이야,이제 다 이겨
That's fire.
Beats everything.
Oh, really? Does it beat water balloon?
정말? 그게 물풍선도 이겨?
잘하는데,피비 정말 잘했어
Well played, Phoebe buffay, well played.
All right, enough, come on. Let's just go in at the same time.
됐어, 그만하고 다들 같이 들어가자
Okay, okay.
잠겼는데?
It's locked.
Wha...?
뭐? 왜 이제야 잠그는 거야
Oh, sure, Now they lock it,
but when they're having sex on the couch, it's like, "come on in. My butt is surprisingly hairy."
소파에서 섹스 할 땐 열어놓고 '내 엉덩이에 털 많죠?' 이러더니
All right, come on.
비켜봐,애들아! 늦어서 정말 미안해
All right, you guys!
We're so sorry we're late!
Please let us in so we can have dinner together.
제발 들여보내줘 같이 저녁 먹자고
안돼! 칠면조도 식었고 소고기도 눅눅해졌다고!
No!
Everything's cold. The turkey's dried out, and the-the stuffing's all soggy!
게다가 크렌베리 소스도..
Yeah, and there's a bowl of cranberry sauce that's... what happens to cranberry sauce?
그건 어떻게 됐지?
Nothing. It's fine.
그건 아무렇지도 않아
Oh, thank god!
하늘이 살렸네!
Come on, you guys. We're sorry. Our-our subway broke down.
애들아, 정말 미안하다고 지하철이 고장 났었어!
거짓말 마, 하키 보러 갔었잖아 조이 손가락이 보인다구!
That's a lie!
You went to the game. I can see joey's hand.
For the love of god, take it off!
젠장! 그거 벗으라니까!
얘들아,늦은 이유가 중요한게 아니잖아 이젠 다들 왔다구!
You guys, come on.
It doesn't matter why we're late. We're all here now.
Please let us in so we can have some of your delicious turkey.
이제 들어가서 같이 맜있는 칠면조나 먹자
예전에 꿈에서 팩스기가 이런 적이 있었다?
I had a dream once about a fax machine that did that.
That's all the turkey you're going to get!
그것만 갖구 먹어
누가 먹을지 어떻게 정하지?
How are we going to decide who gets this?
Water balloon!
물풍선!
이제 어떻게 하지? 배고파 죽겠어
What are we going to do? I'm starving.
Oh, I just remembered!
먹을 게 생각났어! 아침에 모니카가 오븐에 뭘 넣어놨어!
We do have something to eat. Monica put something in our oven this morning.
Hey, you touch that, and you will be sorry.
그거 건들면 죽을 줄 알아!
Guys, I'd listen to her. The vein is bigger than I've ever seen it!
그 말 들어! 핏줄이 정말 크게 섰다구!
Voila.
여기 있어 꺅! 싹이 텄어!
Oh, my god, it's brussels sprouts!
이건 없는 것만 못하잖아!
That's worse than no food!
하! 그래봤자 겨우 모니카가 만든 싹눈이지?!
Ha, ha! All you got was monica's stinky brussels sprouts!
Stinky?
'겨우'라고?
Please let me stay on this side of the door.
자기야 우린 같은 편인 걸 잊지 말아줘
Oh, I know! I still have my old key.
아, 맞지! 나한테 아직 열쇠가 있어!
Ooh.
We can just unlock the door.
그냥 문을 따고 들어가자
Well, I don't know if that's such a good idea.
좋은 생각은 아닌 것 같은데 우리랑 같이 있기 싫다잖아
They clearly don't want to be with us.
You know what? I don't want to be with them either, but it's thanksgiving,
나도 쟤네랑 같이 있기 싫지만 오늘은 추수 감사절 이잖아
똑같이 같이 있기 싫어하는 것 같은 건 싫어!
and we should not want to be together together!
If I could just get in there and make a face-to-face apology,
내가 들어가서 내 눈으로 쳐다 보기만 해도 우릴 봐 줄거야
you know, look 'em in the eye, I know can I get 'em to forgive us.
-I don't know... -I'm telling you...
글쎄..
맞다니까
할 수 있어
I can do it.
그래, 할 수 있겠다
Yeah, he can do it.
좋아
정말 멋져 보인다!
It all looks so beautiful.
칠면조에,소고기에..
-The turkey, the stuffing... -The cranberries.
크렌베리도?
그만 좀 해! 원숭이도 그건 만들겠다!
Enough! A monkey could've made 'em!
얘들아, 정말 미안해
Hey, listen, guys, we feel really terrible.
He's doing that weird eye-contact thing.
또 저 묘한 시선 짓거리를 하네
쳐다보지 마! 쳐다보지 말라구
Don't look at him. Don't look at him.
얘들아, 우리가 정말,정말로 미안하단걸 알아줘
Come on, you guys. We want you to know we're very, very sorry.
그렇지,얘들아?
Right, guys?
-정말 미안해 -미안해
-I feel terrible. -So sorry.
이 날을 망치기엔 니가 고생한 게 아깝잖아
But let's not ruin this day. You've worked so hard.
이 일을 잊고 다함께 같이 먹자, 응?
Let's move past this, and try to have a nice meal all together, huh?
저 머리들 말도 일리가 있는데?
The floating heads do make a good point.
그래 뉘우치는 것 같이 보이긴 하네
Yeah, they do seem to feel pretty bad.
-So bad. -So bad. -So bad.
-맞아 -맞아 -맞아
Okay.
Okay, you two go get the dessert, and I'll let you in.
알았어 너희 둘이 디저트를 가져오면 들여보내주지
디저트?
Dessert?
Yeah, I asked you and Phoebe to pick up the pies.
파이를 갖고 오라고 했잖아 그건 안 잊었겠지?
You did remember, right?
Pies. Oh, we thought you said "prize."
파이라고? 난 또 상이라고 한 줄 알았지
Here.
여기
예쁜 아기 대회?
Grand supreme little darling?
축하해!
Congratulations!
파이는 잊어 먹은 거야?
Oh, my god, you forgot the pies?!
Well, I can't believe this!
나 한테 저녁요리도 시키고 한 시간씩이나 늦더니 내 부탁은 그거 하나도 못 한거야!
You forced me to make dinner, then you're an hour late,
and you forget the one little thing that I asked you to do!
Really, girls, not cool.
얘들아,정말 너무했다
Well, you man-heads aren't any better.
너희 남자 머리도 할 말 없어! 하키 안 본다고 거짓말 했잖아!
You lied about going to the game. You knew it would make you late,
늦을 걸 알면서도 그냥 갔잖아!
and you still went anyway.
Hey! I'm getting a little tired of this, okay.
더 이상은 못 참겠다 미안하다고 했잖아!
We said we're sorry!
용서의 추수감사절이잖아! 용서의 날이라고!
It's thanksgiving, for pete's sakes!
A day of forgiveness!
It's a day to be thankful.
감사하는 날인데?
내가 거기 올라간다, 응?
Don't make me come up there.
It's too late for apologies.
사과하기엔 이미 늦었어
Fine. Let's just go. I don't need your stupid dinner.
좋아!
가자,이딴 저녁 필요없어!
침만 안 흘리면 믿는 척이라도 하겠다
That would be a lot more convincing if you weren't drooling.
Ew! Is that what that is?
이게 침이었어?
미안
Sorry.
Come on, you guys. Let's just do our own thanksgiving.
얘들아,가자? 우리끼리 하자구
Yeah, I'll cook.
-그래 내가 요리할께 -그래 식당으로 가자
Yeah, let's go out.
Hey!
Yeah, you three have a nice thanksgiving.
너희 셋이 추수감사절 잘 보내라
The three of us?
우리 셋 이라고?
Yeah. You, Chan, and the vein!
너랑,챈들러랑 그 핏줄 말이야!
Uh-oh.
I'm stuck
이런,꼈네
Joey, that is not going to work.
조이,그래도 소용없어
No, seriously. I'm...
아니,진짜야
정말 딱 꼈다구!
I'm really wedged in here.
내가 당겨볼게
-I'll pull you through. -Okay.
Ow, ow, ow, ow! Stop, stop!
그만!그만! 이러다 머리 나빠지겠다
I'm worried about damaging my head.
It's a little late for that.
이미 늦은 거 아냐?
어떻게 좀 해봐!
Well, hurry up. You got to do something.
All right, well,
그래도 달라질 건 없어
조이 얼굴에 기름칠할 것 좀 가져와
Okay, we need to get something to grease the sides of his face.
-Uh, we got turkey grease. -Bring it.
칠면조 기름이 있는데?
가져와!
핏줄을 사람이라고 해서 미안해
I just want to say that I'm sorry I referred to the vein as a separate person.
Here you go.
좋아, 시작한다
Ooh, that smells good.
냄새 좋은데?
좋아,한번 빼봐
Okay?
Okay, try it.
안되잖아!
It isn't working!
체인을 빼야겠다
All right, we're going to have to unscrew the chain.
Well, hurry. I can't feel my ears.
귀가 안 느껴져
Can you ever feel your ears?
언제는 귀가 느껴지냐?
흥미로운 걸?
Interesting.
Chandler, where are your tools?
챈들러,연장 어디 있어?
Ooh, I left them on my bulldozer.
불도저에 놓고 왔어
I don't have tools.
내가 연장이 어딨어?
Well, I do, but rachel borrowed them.
내 연장은 레이첼이 빌려갔는데
-I lent them to ross. -I gave them to joey.
그건 로스가 빌려갔어
난 조이한테 줬는데
공원에 놓고 왔어
I left them at the park.
이거 장난치는 걸 참기가 여간 어려운게 아닌데?
I'm finding it really hard not to mess with him.
이미 바지에 싹눈을 넣어놨어
I've already stuffed a bunch of brussels sprouts down his pants.
Nice!
멋진걸?
Okay... I have to get that.
내가 전화 받고 올 때까지 너희들 다 사라져 줘
Now, when I get back, I want you and your friends to be gone.
Thanksgiving is over!
추수감사절은 다 끝났어! 이 핏줄님이 하시는 소리라고!
The vein has spoken!
It's really starting to hurt.
이제 정말 아퍼!
Okay, look, I'm... I'm going to pull on the door,
난 문을 당길테니 너희들은 힘껏 밀어봐
and you guys push as hard as you can.
Maybe we can get enough room to wiggle him out, okay?
그런 다음 조이가 몸을 흔들어 빼는거야 알았지?
Okay, so push!
좋아 밀어!
잠깐만, 지금 좀 뭔가 하는 중 이야
Just a sec. We're kind of in the middle of something here.
Oh! Stop putting things down my pants!
바지에 뭣 좀 넣지마!
얘들아,밀라고!
-Come on, guys, push! -Yeah, come on!
그래, 좀!
Push! Push! Push!
밀어!밀어!밀어!밀어!
My cranberries!
내 크렌베리!
옷에 음식이 다 묻었네!
Oh, man, I got food all over me!
Ah! I can't believe what you did! Monica's going to kill you!
모니카가 널 죽이려 들 거야!
Look, look, look what the... look what...
이거 다 저 머저리들이 한 짓 이야!
look what the floating heads did!
I don't care.
상관없어!
What's going on?
왜 그래?
That was the adoption agency.
입양사무소에서 온 전화였어
And...?
그런데?
We're getting a baby!
입양을 해 준대!
Are you serious?!
정말?
There's a pregnant woman in ohio, and she picked us.
오하이오에 있는 미혼모가 우릴 골랐대!
-정말 잘 됐다 -축하해
I'm so happy for you.
작년 추수감사절은 쨉도 안돼!
This thanksgiving kicks last thanksgiving's ass!
To Monica and Chandler ...
모니카와 챈들러.. 그리고 오하이오의 미혼모를 위하여!
and the knocked up girl in Ohio.
Cheers!
I'm just so happy you guys are finally getting a kid.
너희들이 입양을 하게 되서 정말 기뻐
그러게, 너희 아기도 예쁜 아기 대회에 내보낼래?
I know. Have you considered pagaenting?
I can't believe they called and we are actually getting a baby.
아직도 입양 허가 전화 받은 게 실감이 안가
I know how you feel.
나도 그 느낌 알지?
정말?
-Really? -Sure.
그럼
I went the exact same thing with Alicia May Emory.
나도 내 인형을 받을때 그런 느낌이었지
그 기다림과 혼돈의 시간들..
The waiting and wondering.
그러던 어느날, 장난감 가게에서 전화가 왔지
Then one day I get that call from Toysrus
인형이 창고에 들어왔다는 거야
She was in stock.
그래,아주 똑같구나
That is the exact same thing.